#### Behil Alemu

behilsamuel05@gmail.com | (404) 488-5213| LinkedIn: behilalemu | Github: @Behil-Alemu | Atlanta, GA

### **Summary**:

Full-stack software engineer with experience in Python sseopazand JavaScript, and a background in biology to approach software development with unique problem-solving skills. Skilled in developing full-stack applications and analyzing complex data sets, utilizing frameworks such as ReactJS, Node.js, Flask, and Express, as well as databases like MySQL and PostgreSQL.

### **Technical Skills:**

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript

Frameworks: ReactJS, Node.js, Flask, Express, Jest, Redux

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, GitHub, XML, Markdown

Operating Systems: MacOS, iOS

Testing frameworks: Jasmine, Jest, Unittest, Doctest

Software: Microsoft Office, ArcGIS, QGIS, Visual Studio Code, Slack, ERPLX

### **Projects**:

# Field Recorder web-application

- Web application that is designed for research biologists who need to keep track of samples and analyze data from the NatureServe-API
- Created a website via Node.js, React, Google Maps Api,NatureServe Explorer API, Chakra UI and PSQL. Github link.
  - Integrated Google Maps Api to location pinned sample location

## The Metropolitan Museum of Art API web-application

- Web application that lets users discover art-work from the MET-API
- Created a website via (backend and frontend)Python, JS, Bootstrap, Flask, SQLAlchem, and PSQL. GitHub link.
  - Enhanced user's personal information security features using Bcrypt.

### **Experience:**

### Springboard, Software Engineering Bootcamp (Apr 2022 - April 2023)

- Completed an 800-hour course covering key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.
- Skills acquired include Web Development, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Event Driven Programming, Git/Terminal/Github, Testing, AJAX, ¡Query, Data Structures and Algorithms.

## Alcon, Laboratory Technician(Jun 2023- present)

- Completed all necessary inventories and documentation for lens processing.
- Prepared lenses for clinical trials.

### Dendreon, Manufacturing Operations Associate (Mar 2021 – Apr 2022)

- Adhered to cGMP, PPE, and safety guidelines in highly regulated environment while following batch records and SOPs.
- Executed procedures while securing patient's personal and bio information to support cell therapy.
  - Handled materials, samples, and biohazard waste.

#### **Education:**

- Springboard, Software Engineering Career Track Certificate (Apr 2022 Apr 2023)
- Georgia Gwinnett College, B.S. in General Biology, Lawrenceville, GA (May 2020)